so actually you'll be doing something
like this by the and uh...
summer height zero
with yeah survey class you'll be able to
do
most of this with your own chart
asa don't feel like you're anywhere near
having to be able to uh...
understand what's up on the screen but
if there is a summary video stores show
you what
what you're producing for the whole
process of this semester
and next semester
taxapad class
plus all the extra
outside
lectures right
hardball
training here
what you're looking at a fear
the bag format his thereafter so kinda
like the picture it's got pics
pixels themselves
today we're gonna talk about
how to work with some of these files
were going to see some of the many
aspects and working with bags
they're really neat format
but they have a lot of complexity to
them in terms of different parts
here's a bag
from awful portsmouth right near us
that's actually light our data
and you can see that there's
they only on the shorelines
white art it hasn't worked very well
at the border
it's absorbed by the water column so
doesn't make it down very far
and what i've got up here
parsing through mobile parts of
all the data on and d_d_c_ with fags
some of that is the value box taken out
of the meditative finals
there's a couple
files that originally had
bounding boxes in the wrong place so
will start seeing
how to do in there
freedom edited a check it out read the
great dept data
needed local histogram with a bit
and there's also a second layer called
uncertainty
that's trucked in there
for each grade cell point
so with the uncertainty you can see
what is the effort to quality of that
data
because it will orbit uncertain you'll
see certainty for each grade cell
and you can see how that very over
surveys
what goes on here with bags is there's a
number of different
ways that you know it slices up the bags
for their particular process
and so they're going to put bags on top
each other's opiate differ resolutions
and
sub regions within it deft bands
anything about taxes they actually
started
somewhere along the hallway over there
chips met
and brian calder and a few other people
had the idea of
when you get data for mister bay
and you have more for peace is running
around and they're in different files
it's really easy to lose part of it
and during my ph d thesis i found lots
of metadata files for data that looks
really awesome
i would've loved to included that data
in my thesis from editor
but i could never find the data files
the former about medicaid a thirst
everybody spends a lot of time focusing
on phone numbers at the email addresses
his aunt
at physical addresses and the date is
ten or fifteen years old
that person may have switched jobs
that phone number might not even be for
the same organization
and so it's really tough when these
things are separate out so the i'd won
the ideas of access to put everything in
that in one file together you defined it
all or none of it
the trouble is is that
inside of this container
a lot of programs don't you understand
all these different data types so we
have people pull them apart
double-checked them now a lot of tools
that you guys are going to be using
in a lot of her other classes do you
know about them but doesn't
assertive you as much flexibility as
he'd like when you build aback and
carrots
you get to type in three or four fields
and then
carey says everything else behind the
scenes and doesn't even show you
metropolitan rates it just says here's
your back
and by the way collected
that does not necessarily
a big deal as just know this is the
first pass on
generating bags from within carriage so
what we need to be able to do is
create our own tools that go in and
validate what's in those bags
make sure that what's coming out of
these
you're very expensive programs
is what we want
so the idea i've had
whippet behind his videos being able to
preview every bag indosat
pull up the mega few histograms and
they're in there
and make sure that what's coming out of
these tools
uh... what you expect and now it's
important i think to you
when you're doing what they are
especially complicated stuff like multi
being the chemistry and have her on her
feet
really important to have more pple tools
look at the same data
because there could be a bug in one of
the other
if your tools
and if you have three or four tools that
can all read invalidate that same data
and you're in the morning all agreed
that speed dating at a much better
chance of which are producing in sending
out
being dead
so i'm always going to stress on you
guys that new collecting british data
double check it validated
and validate a couple of different ways
if you can't as kind of pain the but
put lightly
but being able to go in and double
checked the data on your own is
fantastic and we fight all kinds of
mistakes in our own data
and we have a time the engine to double
check
don't always get that
it's in the process of becoming a naive
show ass one hundred acts standard
it's contains item standards
it contains the
and i don't remember the uh...
hyattsville number for
meditative format
but i don't think bag itself is iza
it's difficult burden
in the notes in fact
class eighteen
so i down loaded the uh...
word file for today
that's a perfect question leading into
the first little bit of the class
so opened up sir
is a website
and if you actually traced down where
the says physically on the globe
is about fifty feet that way
so this is the website run by ccom
for the community
their standards for at
dirt background papers there shuts
thesis on here
and the code is all released
under various open-source licenses
so if you wanna read all the sea source
go to the details of this
you cannot
going to that
we're gonna try and avoid betsy and the
library side of it can take a different
route we're gonna look at it
some command-line tools that
no i describe the basic format and
from some pipeline
so act and d_d_c_ which is the primary
day archive four
all geophysical datasets for noah and
many other organizations
probably
rolling back to repository or are too
are
is out working with these folks
the site sometimes can be a little bit
difficult to navigate and that a lot of
text-based and not based interfaces
i wrote a little too low but just
scraped the entire site
using two of you get
it's kind of a precedent download every
single backfire on the website over a
weekend
how we should do that to often because
that kal hard on the networks
since i came to always have a hard time
finding that inside of this
or profile
there's a link
right too
and g_g_ is
marine geology geophysics
and i've linked straight into
some example bags and there's actually a
m
just a web server that you can go
through and it's organized by survey
number
when you see an h in front of a survey
that's high traffic survey
and then they have these numbers just
keep increasing as they do more more
surveys
and we're gonna grab some of these
examples
and take a look at some of these bags
using a couple different tools hopefully
you guys are already gone they made a
class eighteen directory i'm gonna go in
there and i'm gonna grab two surveys
can use this
these two w gets here
pace
were actually go cooperate so hopefully
by the end of class in asia are pretty
good sense of what a bag is at least at
a first pass
will see the graded i want to see
if we get nap time some pictures out of
the actual printed out
inside a bat plywood there's lots and
lots of
great formats
and this is just one of the
several hundred formats that are around
so let's take a peek at what we've got
we've got jeezy compressed files
we also hopefully remember had a
uncompressed uh...
jeezy file
thirty unzip sardarji z
and files get a lot bigger quick
here week
we're gonna run the file command when
things are done
i'm finished
sold in dallas tough sell
so i'll have special
and you'll see that the ending dot bheji
remember that
those extensions are convention
and they could be need anything
sore on file
star dot bheji
here's the first thing wrapped the cover
today
he reports back that this is
hierarchical
data format or
hdlc
there's several different versions of
this
etc
the by this point i'm hoping you guys
are comfortable with that
and to find
if you want me to go
looked more like that i will quick do
the same thing richter bag
ticob agar bags
so if you file
startup times
vhdl file-format
a container
not to uh... like things like that then
car you can put a whole bunch of
different things in there
and there's all sorts of software try
and work with these
uh... unlike zipping tar is designed to
be directly accessing the data
it's meant for scientific they're very
formats
there's a lots and lots of formats like
this they're very similar
but that you have to use different tools
for them so unfortunate things like net
cbf
which is using a program called genetic
mapping tools for team t
and is very somewhere this but yet these
different software libraries and
command-line tools before trying to read
them
so we're gonna walk through a little bit
of taking a look at this
like before we last i mean
i've got some notes about running the mt
five some
and the s_ h_ eighteen fifty six
and you can see if they've been updated
sense
it's actually a
archived knows data from may of two
thousand and and i've seen that a lot of
the files have changed since then
somehow change file names
some have changed
content without the file name changing
without an indication from the file that
changed than protect them
watch out for that
in this case if it
jackson's changed as long as you're
files working it's okay
we're not really to worried about which
version of the files were using
although we're actually going down live
on the old files a little bit and look
at the details of it
sincere some intersting mistakes that
were for jenna merit
that i hope will help you guys
get the for what's good meditate and
what's bad meditate on
so when we're looking at medea
what i think that what you guys to be
thinking about is
meditative when you're producing a it's
hard to think about you know what
someone else who might be consuming your
date is going to need that here
the consumers are bags today
that night is there to help us work what
that data
so first problems with it those are
things that remember for later on when
you're producing a bag
in the spring
think about that when you're producing
the bag what in here was helpful or not
helpful to you in terms of the continent
it's hard to understand what's hopeful
on that day that had people get upset by
didn't include a phone number
india
in the back but the author
doesn't have so they have a phone number
met the person
has changed jobs alone is retired
their office phone isn't useful anymore
so try to remember those kinds of things
and think about the house and ask
questions if you see stuff in that area
that you're curious about
we're going to go over to you
so what you guys to skip a bunch of
notes and see if you can scan down for
that no
if you remember in imax you can you
control at sea
and typed and okayy
and you'll get to where i am notes is so
little
reminder of are forty max trick of the
day
we'll have a couple more later on but
this is a
control s is good
and we're gonna grab
two bags if you look at this web address
were no longer looking at antisera
looking at my web page
and it's under research tools examples
old dash bags
so copy goes to lawrence
control in a
control space down two lines
and meta w
never pesos to win
these file succumbed are really fast
because it is coming down from upstairs
and i've compressed these would be easy
to you because they compressed better
that way
will do a b_ unzipped
startup bag
not be easy to you
ql especial and you should now see
funny file names so one of the things to
think about when you build data files
these are the old files coming from
at the wrong people become from two
thousand ten
these were named h one one seven oh
three sets the survey number underscore
combined
underscore five m
this one was eight one one seven zero
three underscore office
not sure what offices close to being
underscore five m
dot back
when they first heard easing back they
hadn't really come up with a good naming
scheme for and written it down
the names kind of war were all over the
place and people turned out things it's
very confusing in the long run
when you have these schemes that wander
so they've now come up with a new naming
scheme
that's based on a couple of different
things
you'll see that some of them have stud
but they still have a combined
but now they say they have a and b_ for
multi beam
this is the cell size qty and they have
a units in there for me here's hilton
it's there
they also have the vertical tatum in
there
here this is one of forcing is going to
be three others if you actually process
all that
this is a good lesson and
file naming conventions are
nazi
critical you don't have to have them
but they really help a lot so if you get
a hold from the data and the files are
really can physically need it makes life
a lot easier
we're gonna go work with these two files
which are older and hats and parks that
car
illustrations of things
that issue
the bags just addition doesn't say
anything about the naming
and in fact i'm not sure it even says
dot
right so let's start off with some
programs that might know something about
that we've used g doll bunch of times
and let's see if g tall actually knows
anything about this
it's often important to know which
version of
something you're running
so if you'd you'd g dot info dash dash
versions
we're gonna see that we have g tall one
point six point three
released in two thousand nine
a little while ago
the finale chosen eleven
so we're looking at a release from two
years ago
maybe it's not support maybe it doesn't
so we can say gee dol info
each one one
and will do
office because i think the office team
which is kinda
kooky and we're doing fine
and if you hit
enterica doing that so here's the
command
details then try thank you it's best to
actually have to hdfc port
so it's running off to the ship by
driver
but we don't see any indication of the
safe agar anything like that so it's a
little questionable
as we look down here
it saying the fought the file size is
five twelve i five twelve court
assistant as
and it doesn't know the court system
that's a bad sign
so unlimited actually said backwards bag
version one point no or no
that's looks pretty good
it's got some information about some
subset
but i'm going to get on the coordinates
those quarters are probably not anything
real on the air
they go from zero zero
an eight ten c zero zero
if its geographic is a point off of
africa where a lot of data seems to lie
this day doesn't look good
just guessing by that i would say that
we have failed to be able to read it
with this version of do you know
if you guys
rome this command here so this is going
to be
if we ask g all which formats he knows
about what they say g dot info
dash dash formats
enter we get way too much stuff
so we're gonna use the vertical bar for
a fight
were in a private to each rep
dash i says case insensitive
so if you see needed he cracked
i do is all fine
sort of like my staple find some taxed
i haven't showed you an or before
but we can search for some text or some
other text
inside
before so it's going to reuse the
vertical bars and so it's all confusing
so if we save bheji or
beach d_f_
so this is going to say
search for the
the letters bheji or the letters hdl
so and had been that's great here
and then hit enter
and this is going to tell you
all the text back
has inched yes
dragonair lower case or upper case or
any combination of
pcf version for image and not sure what
differences
hdfc five
issued five image and there's no hint of
the word bag anywhere in there
so this version algae tall doesn't cover
bags
you guys don't have access to this
but hopefully a newer versions of your
twenty you'll get uh... new version of g
dot
and so here it pisses me running it on
it
on my laptop
int
two dollars one point eight released in
two thousand eleven july
and this one when i ran that he grabbed
command see you guys
door about rings again because this is a
different machine
actually showed up with
bheji bapteme it the mystery out to be
degraded
so this one actually knows about bags
and can tell you more about them
proportionally our virtual machine with
you go into version that we have we
don't have that supports over i have to
not worry about you all for this format
and try and do other things
so if you look in the parentheses here
question was what was the our old in
here
mrs read only
so the format dick and read through
foreign second-rate and so they can read
and write
so this means it can only read these
formats ticket correct
who still does not know how to create a
bag
correct knowns written the code to write
out a bag from this
it's probably a bad idea for this too
will be able to write bags because it's
not using the bag library becomes from
standard
it has its own coterie banks
and so the chances are that writing it
correct that will be small unless we
put in the code from the main library at
skynet it clashes with some of the stuff
inside of that
today gaskets become system ishares
again we're gonna switch to using the
hdfc five tools and we're gonna go take
a look at the raw data
i'm a big big proponent you can hear me
again again talk about
getting at b
rob it's invites with the lowest level
you can with date of your using
so that you trusted better when you're
using higher level tools in the election
getting into
ceron a ceo
space apts dash to get space install
space
a_t_f_ by dash tools
and if you don't remember the research
tools password
when you see there are two do
route like surgeries are
it's bang arts in two thousand eleven
via
as the power of love about you bring to
you where you can stall for foreign aid
goes pretty quickly
so let's go ahead and try them out
the first we're going to use
content clear to kris kringle
just to give myself some more space you
don't have to do if you don't want to
each five ls
anaerobic anti-family and
for a manual page
and if you want to speed reading
welcome to you
what this does is it says it prints
information about a filer dataset
not very helpful
that we're gonna work through this come
and see if we can take a look at a bag
and we can see
where we have a look at the spectra band
so we're not really going to be a
red-hot because i don't
they want to go reader
the journal paper about it
so will do each five ls
and then
speech one one seven oh three
office underscore five top bag
remember it how does your friend for
completion
and hit enter
and see what you get
surging
doesn't on some question how do i find
always just yet tools
surfing i did
as i didn't know what bags were when i
started
fight down with a bunch air and file
evro back
her kal data format
and i went in the found fares are an
hdfc library
culpa testified
and then i started running things like
cash
search hdlc
which is probably a return a lot of
stuff
to see what was available
and there's you know few things and i
don't
tried a couple i'd say about
four five two a tried first that didn't
work
they were here too old impressed the or
too hard to figure out
and no googling for a_t_f_ five
came up with a few things there's
websites like stock exchange your stack
overflow where you can post questions
saying i'm trying to work with a steer
fried
and i'm not getting it helped
and trying to do acts
this took me
to get the point of showing today
so my hope is that by you guys seeing
that these examples as you probably work
with bags
capitalism the formats
you can skip that week that i had to
spend a stumbling around dark but if you
get a new format that you don't know
that's being brought into a project for
example we have uncovered
you're gonna have to go to that same
discovery process that isn't necessarily
easy
my hope is that this class is the
beginnings of
a document as organic and growth in
starts having more of this when i get
acts
where do i start
and we can get you all the way through
to understand format totally
but this is a kickstart
for banks to get you guys going in the
right direction
and as we had other formats will keep
doing that
and hopefully over the years really keep
growing and so that we have
a master document you guys can get back
at
these formats
do you have a format that you really
really really wanna see before the end
semester
you can you know me and i might
get to a culture it depends on times
some formats are too complicated to get
through
or my taking amounted to really
understand that the court unicycle
i can't promise anything
so let's keep digging through h five ls
in c we can figure out
we're not gonna go back to me engage in
this country is in the stuff i found in
the main page
so we can you each five ls
that platform
just gave us bag britan group
and i'll tell you that when i saw that
it didn't really mean anything to me
some of the recourse
no sincere most of you never take a
computer science class you might not
know what recursive means
for every person
is for
if there's a tree of things
we have kind of a route
and you've got
notes below it
and some other stuff down below
this is a sort of our heritage prints
recursion is exp walking down the street
and walking over each of these nos
going over it
if you see like directory things or
change for missions would see a smart
nixonian schiavo it has a dash are for
the first that that will go then down
into the tree
so we're gonna go ahead and run out
and we get a little bit more
so now we're certainly get something
that looks like
whom i care about it because backward
and group
but inside of
bagri we actually see there's elevation
merited a
tracking west uncertainty
those look like things really care about
with
uh... photographic survey data
now i don't know what the tracking
listed in never actually looked in there
then you've got a security if you can
figure that one out let me know before
but we're going to look at the medicare
which is actually prior so exim element
data
describes what's in here
elevation is a
graded a regular parade of the
elevations
so it looks like a picture of the c_
four
an uncertainty is
how well we know each of those positions
inside
elevations so we're going to go ahead
and try to dig into the stuff a little
bit more
right now
a matrix is that i thought way of
thinking about this yes
i believe that that's
that's fine i'm not really sure what the
foreigners here on the right
i believe this is the wit
and not height
of the cells company
this but be a number of lines
not really a gritted format this is this
strings
and we received this is very confusing
it's not perform format with the school
it doesn't really understand strings
very well
all show you how i read it
painful how i read it
that'll do it by pomodoro your life
warranty now is we're trying to get that
medicaid
it said tell us what this is about its
always did this for a start off with a
revealed no datafile if you can find one
so what we're going to you because we're
gonna use
syringes had action dean
why don't we just do a man page on it
nixonian you guys don't transfer mammals
group on the screen
each five hello summer look first watch
d
prints the values of the day to reprint
the med in see what it does
so will say
each five ls dash d
the file name
after lots of googling and struggling i
think there to help protect
you can paste the path
to what you're looking for
right on what the file name
which is both cool and weird
copy paste
foods tacked on
figures are file name
and then here's the path of inside of
p_h_d_ at five p_m_ and hit enter
and that's really gross
not burns going back on it
rerun that with piped to head
we'll take a peek at this
so here's the commanding ram
if you can read half though is quote
super talented so it's
angle bracket question x ml
so this is a format we actually care a
lot about where an alarm about
that's mustard x and those are really
useful way store data
this is not a very useful way this play
it's about
webquotes around every single character
and it looks like this is uh...
character position so i think we have
eighteen characters at here
that's just miserable
and i actually spent hours trying to
figure out how to ask the same to please
not do that and just tell me what in
there
because taxed
and still have open questions out there
on their net hoping someone will tell me
because i can't figure it out
so let's go ahead and write a command
that well
turn that doing something we care about
this can be a long time and here
so the first thing we want to do is we
want to get rid of these first two lines
the meta data and the data
i'm gonna use that same grep command
grep is like my humor but i attack
everything with
and we're gonna basically
and say we want to find everyone that
has a quote in it
so all is horrible stuff
kinda helpful actually
because we can ask for everyone who has
a quote so we can say preparation of
written he crept
doesn't matter
similar search for
and at the protective a single quotes
veritable pro character
animal wiped out too
head again to see what we get
as we build up our command
here's the command
and if rates go back just a little bit
so you can see the last one
we were trying to get rid of those two
lines
and they're not here anymore
so that got rid of those first few lines
buy triad returned the lines just to
have quotes in them
so now we've got a face off with the
quotes because they suck
so we're going to say cut
now i have to back up because i want
each of these characters on the single
line
type at the head again and
there's another option two option for
bath adhere one is dash dash during
and the others dot staff simple
simple size
all of these guiding each character on
its own line
hit enter
we get rid of the swine number
and we put each one
parts online
so we had
those to you guys right there
because he's already not being very fond
it's pretty calm belligerent
were actually getting quotes
so what we can do now as we can use our
old friend cut
and we can cut
on the field woman her equals
and we can grab that middle section of
text
so if we say
dashed deep
and nothing's get funky because we're
trying new things like people finds that
have special needs this shell
if you put up backfires in front of the
character
it prevents it from acting like a
national quote to pull the string
will put a backslash quote
the seeing some kind of advance shell
scripting stuff
and we can save dash af
indicated by you think which field we
want without sneaking a peak down below
there for cutting on
there's a letter of the quote
it's kinda like a comma-separated value
file but we're getting quotes of the
bizarre
this is field one
this is field to missing field three
through on a crowd guilty
going to convince you that the school is
no fun
amplitype hadn't we now see that we've
just seen
when you got to get close to being a
religious read x ml
and all tax was like this
from files of the dot on dot
and we have a one last problem
if we don't want all of this on
different lines one o'clock in the
gather
we can use a command called t_r_
translate
to translate that newline character into
it's kinda weird option newyear
translating from one character to
another like a changing
ka most out of town there is something
like that for csd to a taboo on the file
but we can do
tiara
and if you give its dash
deal which is run off my screen
kisses when long command-line search
here really annoying
so we're going to be doing this guy
right here
so the judge d
rep backslash character protects things
and also has special meaning sometimes
so slash and is the new line character
we're gonna pipettes alas president had
because we're gonna get a lot of text on
one line
quartet lasts
what you guys go ahead and take that and
and press return when you're ready
hopefully you'll see some
taxable it's a little more readable
won't be very fun though
tell me what's in this file
now that sucks you know if you if you're
used to reading it you can start seeing
things like that they in here
and it was quite in two thousand eight
the greatest we can do better
so let's say that to a file
so if we do
greater then rather than uptight so
we're gonna send it to a file
recall it the same file name
but with uh...
it'll look like this bombing
sold student head
so it's just the same thing as our so
here's our input file
and we've changed
the dark bag intuit dot excel
enter
now do an ls dash l
and we have a new file
there's the maximo
and i'm missing you guys back to you
he mac school
tools taking max
clients
pesach
no dash weight
torricelli max please at this file for
us
one one seven uh...
office haven't
so when you enter on this you mac should
pop up with fax in all file
go-ahead hit and i'm not
elite upper second you guys
ed please with he max is colored a
little bit sold some of the keywords are
at least highlighted
so you get blue and red
you know if you're black
ami of one three
uh... to an hour staff cell and take a
quick look at the retreat
see how we have a zero point file
yeah thruster excellently distilled
fighter
if you look appear in your command i see
a vertical bar aimed at
the uh...
presents
that basically suckered into nothing
and so he apparel twice
and more time
and delete that before
past-life
one of those things were typing accuracy
and
lots of brain and almost looks like a
random character generation you know
if u leave like for example operable bar
reading here from before when you have
here
about the column weekend travel
i'll go ahead and run that commands
aneesh you see something like that
you can control see that
teens and happy
uh... down here he max is confused
so it wonders is asking you that sort of
of the files as the one reloaded
so-called yes
once when
history
successfully
instead
so now we're staring at
it's not the kind of runs together and
i'm gonna start bringing had similar out
of the do you think he has fought that
is here
in x_ amount
it's a format
has tags around data
so if you have a field like date
the way you story date in x amount if u
but angle brackets around this is public
tag
and then you might have to tell them
eight dash
hopeful as dash eleven
so the says he has a
may eleven
and then you and your tags and i'm gonna
forget which way this classrooms
fast
if your team at this point the fact that
i was not valid that totally true
this ex-military not valid
it's got all kinds of problems document
ok uh...
i would expect that you probably have a
that while walking in it
so to go back here
if you do hello special
whatever deal is bring us up to you can
see the bottom
few medha acts
all tax
revert dash buffer
press enter
type yes
uh...
unit at the fall and not sure why you
are sitting still
making like a key
where i come back and read it directly
with right on the minute
all this can be hiding between these
tags
and their software that's designed to
parse this four-year so when we get the
papon
this is going to be easier
because our special tools that
explosively for this
so you can just ask for community animal
and go find it for you
but where do you see you next little bit
and this is a common thing that i do
with really badly formatted data
so i want to have you guys heat atleast
once
how he might take something that looks
like
as terrible as this
and turning something useful
so if you look at one of these tags
during the morning here
in this walk attacks
this is the swatch saying this is the
end of the westbound longitude
anderson beginning at least balloting
everytime to tags butt up against each
other
there's a greater than last them
if we take that tax and splitting for a
new line in there between every single
one of the stuff to file
if they take each tag input on one line
and as you get used to work in the files
like this you'll see patterns like that
where if you
replace something you can take some hits
all run together and figure out where
shoving nuance in might actually look a
lot cleaner
to look at bat ago
and there's a instructions rate in the
election without a doubt simon do matter
less then to go the top of the file
and i'm lou do you
medha acts
replace stirring diamond
hit enter
and now on their place one string with
another string
sore intake
greater than life span
ever replace that
greater them
control g
so what you've got it you've got your
region selected here's seats dual
medalist them
or anything but only in the fall so
when you get that less than a trillion
shifty
sinn fein so
shift meta and then the com are less
than
circling back to the king of file fears
life and
this is beginning or file
and matter
greater van
goes to that
and the file
so we'll keep using those
nauman also show you something else
that's really
kinda crazy but we really helpful
if we wanna insert an entertaining
kinda hard typically to put and enter
key in there
so we have to do
c_q_ is a very special committee max
that says the next yeah i did it
for in the letter offering than it is
kinda crazy
if you do
fit down arrow key you have the same is
controlled j
food aliases for each other
so control jaise down or i'd like to
enter
feed usc jerry
that's gonna put into our placed in
strengthening wine character
so if your control
keel
control jr
and you don't think that
appear in their then we've now scooted
down
from here
over here showing that were a for adding
a new life
so i recommend
active because our clocks today try to
get on your own term replacing a few
things just take it
a dummy file like this and just replace
a bunch of stuff and see how it goes
takes practice to get used to you
replacing these things
and then i would you agree to them
soria lost them
this is pretty heavy duty he max here
but once you get used to this if you're
comfortable with replacements you can
take files that are completely messed up
are not in the form you want
in the few he strokes
rearranged in the way you want some
ahead answer
havier told a man stepping confused
verdana reset and and and refused to you
can just then ignore all this and move
on
so we've now hit enter
and we have some that looks a little bit
more
like what we want
mata last and go back up the top
and now it looks a little more friendly
we have something or actually has one
minute says date
there's a date mayor anandhi
so it's right in the notes so great here
this is how i wrote outback commands
meta x replace dash during
occur in a character
alaska and character
this is this is not exactly a space
oppressed of return key
i did a great event
control heal
controlled j
and then a left and and then to run the
command in the press enter
okay right
tractor
is trying to it if they're funky mode
we're trying to interpret things if you
could have been asking character for
returning there it's been a
get confused
policy if the purpose
accused
yes yes altogether
yes that's it
president excellent way of doing it
for just that we had a good point that
if you're somewhere like this you can be
one of them summer undo that
if we take one of them
and they put we had an terry here
and we copy of this
sify how it that region
medha wm
edit copy
now we can do u medha acts replace
stirring
and lekin then type
grier then lots then press enter
and then i can do a control wide to
paste or if you do at its controlled
even start earlier
somatic w copy that penalty meta acts
replace
stirring
griffin mustang
and then a minority gang control wyatt
and then
headhunter
and i will do the same thing
summer say one last command and then
we're gonna go away from you maxine guys
could take a little break from the team
x craziness
didn't con men and lets them
yep now do u men acts
and then replace
pestering
then do your look
proved in less than that
and then to you
greater band
control field
control jake
and unless they are
press center
certainly haven't gone at this point go
ahead and just watch what we're gonna do
and to try it out later on pick a time
when we're not in class
we're gonna do one more crazy commands
this is a command i love the max for
gold medal less then get yourself for
the very top of that file
press control space two-star marking a
region so says mark activated
use that
and if i ll commander here
it's a matter
career then
so now i've selected the entire file
and in fact meta acts
indent
daschle region
press enter and it's going to invent all
of the sax and also that it has a little
more visual meaning to it
so every kind of attack inside of the
tag is gone and done for a little bit
so looks more oil but like
programming source code
summit enter
and go back at the top so mad i lost
them
and we are now staring at
somewhat better formatted exim allen is
actually kinda messed up it's got some
problems that
and have a poll that output
you really start seeing that
this is your first view of overly
complicated x_ amount
so inside here we have responsible party
and five day they've got some other
weird responsible party and then
individual name
here we have a vigil that's names chief
specific typographic branch
so i'd like to meet that person
uh... organizational name noah
and this is we're percent twenty
floating around that
which is comming nor
that's part of a problem this is not
really dollars there
position name
yes
i believe that this
yes probably there's also a
quote uh... maybe it's a quote
figure that's for sure that support
their yet we're not doing that too much
the whole point of this is not that we
have great data
it's that we can read a little bit
so it looks a little bit more related
and you can start seeing things like
this is great you know of this error the
final
are titleist bag file created from
and colin
p_r_o_ three to two surveys
h one one seven three carats yuki office
blah blah blah blah flaw
that's probably not but i don't think he
wanted to your survey
openness is office
h_m_s_
if you put that on the map
and gave it to say any armstrong is the
title of your back
he might be little frustrated
there's some troubles and here at that
and uh... i don't care suspects this yet
hopefully it's on there but let's
there's no way to enter the title so it
took just the path to the file that you
used to build the bag
as the title
and some of them are like
not for really slash temp slash working
directory slide cellblock
so this is my first thought my goodness
these father really what i want but
neither is the way we can work through
it
and the abstract down here talks about
that there's uh... surveyed
buy food wrote
photos
and you can start getting some
information about the survey
ended the day
saturday
yes so there's lots of troubles with
bags bags are are fairly new and we're
still working through the courts
so what i think we're gonna do in this
class hopefully is i met unpack all
these native files from the giant blah
blah about
engineering credo the sovereignty the
work of grabbing them all for you see it
all
if we all downloaded several terrified
to hear from our
we just kill the network for no good
reason
so at this
don't worry bout anymore if you're in
the middle filling is press control g
and you can fight back
gota potthurst
and go back to your org file
and just put this away
a little painful but it's good to see a
few times
writing for the data
we're gonna go off and
gota pipeline
because i'd done as much friendlier for
this kind of stuff
if you're really come to a team access
not bad
but we start off with a source of david
just stank
about the format file
they we had to do weird quote removals
and
that's just the recipe for disaster
nellie thesis in this regime again in a
minute
there now we should be on bags from
fight on
he can't find it you can always go to
top
do you control us
so you can show us search amber inside
the a_t_f_'s from pipeline
so we need to install a tool
called python dash eight five five
and this is a module
is designed to reduce the f five inside
a python
so if i come we have a little more
control over what's going on
i think of our installed along the safe
and
paste them into a panic paste
so for me it was already installed so
there was here who install
to appear in the second time it doesn't
hurt bang
and now go ahead
i mean do clear you don't have to and
just i i i font
bring to go back into the world the
pipeline
ever and he is this a tripod module two
read the bag
and it should be easier to see what's
going on in the compliance and stuff
for a big fan being able to spot liens
fuel economy or because of the plot does
it look great
then you know you're kind of on the
wrong track
word you don't need the dust as pilot
eating within the class
directly
and then installing the latest install
when you install software to wrap to get
it's gonna install into the operating
system as a whole
for profiteering doesn't matter
there's other ways to install python
that are going to drop things all over
the place and leave you with the
confused mess or hopefully an organized
mess that
someone off for now but you might know
display it's a part of their operations
to diffuse the radar pipe on this
district there
and the notes are missing
this do you think import
h five pine
to get the module
and press enter
and now we're going to go ahead and use
each five pi to load up our bank file
and start playing with
issue five and i hope
this isn't necessarily easy place to be
less confusing than the command line
stuff
for the rich by prime
period
andrew compressed tab
and you'll see all the command center in
there
don't expect that to be super easy but
at least you can read through them and
see what's going on
brittany's beach five five dot
if you're just getting going on this and
you weren't
in the class
if you're reading instructions are fine
tutorial on this
each pot pie dot file
single quote
capital each
pressed tab and it's gonna show you the
files that are not directory
so we want
another one
animals you office
bheji
so this is the commander gonna wanna run
for your second command for a member of
the typing tab
up about
if you press the enter
you create a
an object but he did not choose to gain
a variable
who are actually seem someplace
summer say that into a variable called
bag
to go ahead and hit enter on this
and float up backfire
you can try playing at least tight
became a hit answer here
so this is going to say that
to you
ever go call bag mccann tycoons if you
go
and we'll tell us what's in our
environment
so here's our
three could be a g
period of time
and see what a bag will do for us
there's are a couple of functions on
this that will tell us what's in there
i had to go digging through find them
there's values
to go ahead and try that
uh... in violence one terribly exciting
and we also had
items
maybe a little bit more helpful
not terribly
but what we can do this
so this is uh... i hurt
for three
of thinks it's not think that you def
but we've got
slash
and then bag
this is one thing with the next thing
backwards
underneath bag were is a bunch of stuff
and we want to go see what's down under
there
so it kind of works like an array or a
dictionary that we've seen before
so we can say
equals the bag
use the square brackets and say slash
bag
so here we solved contains a slash bag
route
so we do that
we have this route object
that israeli here's this is our roots
variable
so we don't have to worry about up here
anymore
cantors
ignore that
and we can say groups
items
and it gets much more interesting so he
stepped on a level underneath here
we have
elevation
and then
meta data
followed by
tracking list
the one that i have yet to look into
and then
uncertainty
so we can go ahead and
gravity at applebee's and hopefully aged
five five oh here is a much nicer
interface if you are
decided
it's forest yes five
so it doesn't necessarily think
specifically about bags
on the command line at schools tend to
be a little bit clunky
when you're in python they expect to be
digging today too much more
especially with python having always
built-in functions for plotting and what
not
it's going to give us things we can
actually work with
so let's go ahead and go round
demanded a doubt
so please stay metadata
equals bag
bag roots
slash medicare
they should give us
the medicare didn't complain that's nice
if we say tight
meditative
we get that it's a age five pi
high-level thing is that
i'm not really sure what that means but
you don't sound too bad
if we see omitted ada
sub-zero since we think this is a list
of things
we get backed up first character the
respect that left and
this a dot value
we actually get
that this turns into an array
and we can see the beginnings of barack
some al
seek after reading the things
and know what to expect
unfortunately i knew
that uh... looking for an external
document and so i start seeing uh...
less than a minute
the being of ethanol hatter
in python we had a joint command
detective individual
things including together is strains
so we have an array
of all these letters so what we can say
is
armidale
underscore taxed
equals
and what i think that wild about joining
us you can join our and destroying
animalistic everything right up against
each other
somebody would join
and meta data
dot value
press printer
nothing happens
but hopefully we tied meta data
text
and since i know this is a string and
it's going to grab the first hundred
characters out of it
do not go lower rates life bang
press enter
and we actually see that we have
the beginnings of iraq's ml meta data
that we had before
don't worry right now about the details
of men it is too much
ordinary
will spend a lot of time about it
but you know what act elector brothers
yep plot
stared at it all day and so let's go
ahead and see if we can try to cut out
from the data
something real
let's go see if we can deal with the
elevation
because that's gonna be agreed that we
can make a picture of
solicit elevation
equals
the same weird address whatever thing
back to underscore route slash elevation
it's trying to make us think that this
is like house on the file system
and i'm a cheap and grab just feel the
values right away
analysts right
type elevation
surprise apprised to get back in nam hai
away
that's kinda cool
so we have an array of data that we can
work with
they're trying to make it easy for us
so we can ask out what to do that is
that it's a elevation
and a ship disarray is actually a grade
or a matrix of
fourteen hundred by two thousand
cells
what i would just tryin
and after a dual minimax assist you with
god in their salsa elevation
okay i think it's probably meters i
think senior member singing m hiding in
there they didn't show you guys
volcanoes that's not very nice
to pretty big elevation boast response
who happens to the consent from
map fought live import
hi plot
we didn't do
dash dash pylon so we have to bring in
hi plot
which they were overflying stuff is
hiding something
elevation
amber and i hope this works
this is a like you know
hail mary give it a go
what's gonna happen
it might take a little bit a time
because
this is kind of a big array of stuff
that there's a lot of pointed stuff
working hard times two thousand
cells
and we're hoping a plot will show up
sometime soon
i'm pretty sure it's working hard
we are
we have tech show for the first time
tools that prior fought dot show
presenter
now is working hard
that doesn't look too good to me
pat but that's probably not a bag
or at least
it's not how about your book
what we've got here is we've got a
little bit of trouble on that
we need to rearrange this to make it
useable for this outcome
all we need to
find the right program that plus the
fuckin image
and there's actually something very
specific design for that
sewer pipe lock dot r_e_m_ standing for
image show and elevation
pressed enter
and
hopefully on your screen will be
something that looks
lately like it might be useful
horribly useful
but getting there
the trouble is is that that really a
large number in the max
back to our maximum value
one million
when it doesn't have any data in the
seller rights one million as the uh...
elevation in that cell
and so it's trying to plan image with a
really wide contrast arrangements taking
all like you to write down near zero
it's getting collapsed down into blue
so we need to do some to improve that
traversal section here were essay can we
make this plot more useful
and what we want to do with replace in
not array
all of those big values with something
called me and
and we know it man stands for
not a number ip
and matt bartlett understands nine
number and won't try to do anything with
it whereas when it sees a million says
okay i got a really big number also it
to you
so we're gonna write
some crazy code here that tries to go
through our ray and replace all those
big numbers with a man
from milwaukee guys through it and it's
going to bring in bits and pieces of
stuff we've done before
and we start working with grades
you end up doing things like this
all the time
base with walked the whole fell every
cell in the parade
do something to eat point in the cell
and so on their so will say
acts in
range
elevation
keep that up there don't do i want him
to show you some real quick
so we had an elevation
dot shape
and that's our
acts than our why with sinner heights
sorority use those two things in there
for elevation dot shape
we need them by inspector warren
alright control c
keyboard interrupt
imports num prime this is going to get
us are numbed by it
which is a floating point number which
one prints just princess anne and
doesn't have very good health
to go back and we'll start over with
this now that we have our name available
and we're gonna grab at first shape
value
personally our whip
system account from zero to one must
that are wet
through overall the axis
and then for each acts were going to go
through all the winds
for why in range
elevation
dot shape
height
in in um... why they have some nights
uh... function i'd access cells
he thinks is clear brackets and you
could say acts karma wine
sourcesafe if
if elevation
x come a wine
i don't really know the raise the data
so we can in the military status no the
ending of positive is not in the water
column
so we're gonna get rid of anything
that's above zero fits up in the sky
above ground
we'd we don't want it so we'll see
grier then zero
if it's greater than that we're gonna
set
that value to be there
source the elevation
served acts calmer winds
equals
nam fine
dot man
now there's lots of potential here for
typos
the type a carefully
press enter
i'm so it's done
angled at a coffee
that i don't think this is the best way
to do this
there's probably weighs their way more
efficient to live over a whole array
but this
is obvious early spoke with more obvious
when a magical do everything command
how you got to work with a triangle
things as you go
so now we have
a new thing without having to go back to
our plot commands
single plot
i thought the in the show elevation
ekata suggest before you enter telling
us that here
press enter
antics all the time
and that looks more like within the jury
to me
who have gotten rid of all of those
values that will really big
and turn them in the man's
map file lib eleanor's them
and says i'm not going to worry about
those in my image contrast
and we now have some notes like a little
basin in here and cindy plott's
laxatives
i'm just taking it slowly through this
and i
i'm making a point user so i haven't
done a lot of stuff too much before
so i haven't gone until details of the
things possible
you could probably spend the next two
years getting better at pollen
and still have a lot left
with his command
remember that you can always do
question mark aiding their read up on it
and conceived or something like that you
can set your
see map is color map
i'm not sure whitmore
but these guys are
i believe
this is the transparent colorful alpha
and there may be something in here
weaker down through it that says how to
do something like that
analogy read up on all the details that
a lot
the best thing we're not politician if
you're looking for some specific like
that is to go to the gallery
into keeping fine example
uh... doing something like that we're
going to have like make a colorado
a range of things go away or particular
value go away
and they might have elected to import
for you
i'm gonna stop here and will continue
next time
and will be some histogram ng
will plot up the uncertainty
and will start digging in that matter
data and see what the name says this
they're good or bad
meta data annex ml you guys are seen as
for the first time
so expect you'll be overwhelmed
but just keep falling through it and
hopefully
with a bunch of examples overtime else
are becoming more more comfortable and
you'll get used to reading lots and lots
of angle brackets
these guys
this character steep
to receive lots and lots of
an angle brackets
and after a few hours availed it awhile
but better never gets a greasy